novoresume.com 2019-04-02

# Privacy Policy of Novorésumé | Novorésumé

This chapter informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of the Personal Data we receive from users of Novorésumé, in accordance with the laws of Denmark and the European Union regarding the data protection.

By using Novorésumé, you agree to the collection and use of information in agreement with this policy.

Novorésumé acts as a data controller.

_ (Disclaimer: Novorésumé is a product of Novorésumé ApS, meaning that the Privacy Policy found below applies to Novorésumé. When there is a reference to „Novorésumé”, „us” or „we” this takes into account the following: novoresume.com, Novorésumé ApS, website, site or any other application/app/service/software directly related to Novorésumé and owned & developed by Novorésumé.) _

## 1\. What personal data does Novorésumé use?

When you sign up/register as a Novorésumé user, you provide us with your basic information, as well as any other data you want to be included in your resume, cover letter and/or online portfolio or data that might help Novorésumé to provide you assistance in your job seeking & career development. Furthermore, if you wish to use the Novorésumé premium features, we might also ask for payment details.

The mandatory personal data to create an account includes your first and last name, e-mail address, and password. You are required to provide data which is necessary to create a personal account and use Novorésumé. Your refusal to provide this data determines that you cannot use Novorésumé.

We recommend that you keep your account data updated at all times.

Like many web/app/software applications operators, we also collect information that your browser sends whenever you visit Novorésumé. This Log Data may include information such as your computer's Internet Protocol („IP”) address, your location (city, country), browser type, browser version, and the pages of Novorésumé that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages and other statistics (hereinafter Personal Data).

## 2\. How does Novorésumé use your personal data?

We use your Personal Data only for purposes related to Novorésumé, as following:

  * Operate Novorésumé and provide you the best services described on Novorésumé, like to verify your identity when you sign in, autocomplete the templates with the information that you provided.

  * To customize Novorésumé services and provide you a personalized experience and advertisements that will relate only to our services & products may appear on Novorésumé.

  * Update you with operational news and information about Novorésumé, e.g., to notify you about changes, upgrades or security updates.

  * Provide you with information that you request from Novorésumé or, and with marketing information about products and services which may interest/benefit you for your job searching and career.

  * Send you relevant and informational content that might interest or inspire you in order to help you at all the stages of your career.

  * Carry out technical analysis to determine how to improve the services Novorésumé provides.

  * Monitor activity on Novorésumé, like to identify potentially fraudulent activity and to ensure compliance with the user terms that apply to Novorésumé.

  * Manage our relationship with you, like by responding to your comments or queries submitted to us on Novorésumé or asking for your feedback or whether you want to participate in a survey.

  * Manage our legal and operational affairs.

  * Provide general administrative and perform functions and activities.

  * Management of our CRM tools to provide a better, efficient and personalized communication & experience related to Novorésumé's products and services.

While ensuring the safety of your data, Novorésumé may link the personal data we have collected about you through the multiple channels: the use of our website/apps, newsletter subscription, name, email, city, country and information using cookies from 3rd parties (data from 3rd parties does not contain information about you as an individual, but the overall audience) concerning your interests, demographics, preferences (e.g.: age group, academic background, job preferences.). The purpose for this is to perform general marketing research including customer analysis and customer segmentation and statistics. Furthermore, we may use the information to evaluate and assess your interests and preferences in order to personalize your job seeking/career orientation and website/apps experiences and optimizing the service you receive from Novorésumé.

If you have signed up to receive Newsletters, then Novorésumé will also use your personal data in order to adapt the content of Newsletters to better suit your interests and to provide you with personalized offerings.

Novorésumé may utilize third party service providers that will store & have access to and process your personal data. If such third party services providers process & control your data outside of the EU, such transfer of personal data will either be subject to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield or the European Commission’s standard contractual clauses. When utilizing our services within EU, we minimize the transfer of data as much as possible outside EU, for example, we try to use as much as possible the cloud infrastructure within EU, but some emails, payments process, etc. might also be conducted in accordance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield or the European Commission’s standard contractual clauses.

If you are using Novorésumé services outside EU-U.S. or the European Commission’s standard contractual clauses, for better performance and experience of our products and services, with your explicit and separate consent from this privacy policy, we might temporarily store your data and deliver content & services that support Novorésumé through cloud servers located outside EU/EEA or US.

## 3\. How long does Novorésumé keep your data?

The data and information that identify you as an individual will be kept on our servers as long as they are needed, but no longer than 6 years since the last usage of Novorésumé. E.g.: you might want after a couple of months or years to Sign In to your account to update your job application when looking for a new job.

## 4\. What authorizes Novorésumé to process the data as a data controller?

Novorésumé has the following lawful bases to process personal data:

 **Execution of the agreement**

The legal basis for processing the personal data of the interested party which is collected is the execution of the service agreement. In this regard, the interested party is obliged to provide that data necessary for its execution. If we are not provided with this data, our services can’t be performed.

 **Legal obligations**

The sending of feedback questionnaires about the services, results which will be used to know users' opinion and how the services can be improved.

 **Consent**

In relation to the following purposes, the legal basis for the processing of the personal data of the interested party will be the consent of the same, in cases where it has been given:

  * Management of the registration on the web.

  * Management of the registration on Novorésumé apps.

  * Management of the registration on Novorésumé services.

  * To respond to the exercise of your rights, queries and complaints on the part of the interested party.

The withdrawal of consent of said processing on the part of the interested party may affect the execution of the service agreement.

 **Legitimate interest**

In relation to the following purposes, the legal basis of the processing of the personal data of the interested party will be the legitimate interest of Novorésumé.

  * The drafting of profiles, as described at Section 2.

  * The sending of feedback questionnaires on the services used in order to know their opinion and improve them.

Our legitimate interest consists of being able to guarantee that our website/services/apps remains secure, and to help Novorésumé understand the requirements, expectations and degree of satisfaction of the users and, consequently, improve the services, products and brands. All these actions will be performed to improve the degree of satisfaction of the customer and guarantee a unique browsing and shopping experience.

## 5\. How does Novorésumé share your Personal Data with others?

 **A. Third Party Service Providers**

We may share your personal data with our trusted third party service providers, who, on our behalf, operate, maintain, and/or support our IT systems and IT infrastructure, services, our websites/apps, manage our payment solutions, perform statistical analysis, send newsletters, display you promotions related to Novorésumé and provide you tips for your job search and career development with content created by Novorésumé, provide customer support and perform other important services for us.

 **B. Legal Successors**

A transfer of your personal data to another legal entity may occur as part of a transfer of our business or parts thereof in form of a reorganization, sale of assets, consolidation, merger or similar, in the event of this scenario we will contact you beforehand by email on your Novorésumé email account.

 **C. Other disclosures**

In addition to where you have consented to a disclosure of the personal data or where disclosure is necessary to achieve the purpose(s) for which, it was collected, personal data may also be disclosed in special situations, where we have reason to believe that doing so is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against anyone damaging, injuring, or interfering (intentionally or unintentionally) with our rights or property, users, or anyone else who could be harmed by such activities, or otherwise where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

## 6\. Cookies, Pixels, Conversion Tracking

Like many websites/apps, Novorésumé uses „cookies” to collect information. You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of Novorésumé.

Within Novorésumé, cookies are used to facilitate features and functions which improve your browsing experience. They are also used to measure the performance of the website/app and how visitors navigate their way around. Novorésumé uses them to save your log-in information so that it will make your access to the website/app faster and easier.

Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which are downloaded to your device when you visit a website/app. Cookies are then sent back to the originating website/app on each subsequent visit, or to another website/app that recognizes that cookie. Cookies are useful because they allow a website/app to recognize a user's device. Cookies do lots of different jobs, like letting you navigate between pages efficiently, remembering your preferences and improving the user experience. They can also help to ensure that adverts you see online are more relevant to you and your interests, job seeking process & professional development.

Novorésumé may also use so-called „pixel tags”, „web beacons”, „clear GIFs” or similar means (collectively, „Pixel Tags”) in connection with some site pages and HTML-formatted email messages to, among other things, compile aggregated statistics about Site usage and response rates. A Pixel Tag is an electronic image, often a single pixel (1×1), that is ordinarily not visible to Site visitors and may be associated with Cookies on the visitor's hard drives. Pixel Tags allow us to count users who have visited certain pages of the Site, to deliver branded services, and to help determine the effectiveness of promotional or advertising campaigns. When used in HTML-formatted email messages, Pixel Tags can tell the sender whether and when the email has been opened.

To improve Novorésumé's services, better understand your needs, preferences and provide you the best experience using Novorésumé, we use third-party cookies and pixels which allows us to:

  * Create better content that you will enjoy and will improve your job searching process & career.

  * Deliver you exclusive discounts, promotions and seasonal offers that will save you time and money.

  * Conduct testings for simplifying our services and creating the best features which will skyrocket your career.

  * Show you tailored content for your region and unique examples, tips, and tutorials following the local recruiting trends.

  * Measuring our services performance in order to improve & deliver the best experience.

This website/app has integrated content belonging to third parties on this website/app. These third-party providers can place cookies while you visit the website/app, and in doing so can obtain information about the fact that you have visited the website/app. Please visit the websites belonging to those third-party providers if you need more information about how they use cookies. If you have decided not to provide your consent to the use of cookies that require it, or if you have revoked that consent, then you will only be provided with website/app features whose use does not require such cookies. Areas of the website/app that can potentially incorporate content from third parties, and which therefore place third-party cookies, will not be available to you if that is the case. If you do not want to accept cookies at all, then you can also configure that in your browser. You can learn more [here](https://novoresume.com/page/legal/legal-links).

Disabling/enabling cookie

You can accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. However, you will not be able to use all the interactive features of Novorésumé if cookies are disabled.

Most recent web browsers allow control over the cookies saved through the browser setting.

## 7\. Security

According to the Danish „Act on Processing of Personal Data,” on the protection of individuals concerning the processing of personal data and the free movement of such data, modified and supplemented, Novorésumé is required to manage safely and only for specified purposes, the personal data you provide about yourself.

As per this Privacy Policy, as mentioned beforehand, Novorésumé will always strive to protect your Personal Data, but if you choose the option of sharing your professional documents through our sharing option (this includes sharing the link to your digital application or by sharing your documents for receiving feedback) on 3rd party software, websites/apps or services you do it with your consent and at your own risk acknowledging that Novorésumé cannot be held accountable for what happens with the personal information after your share it outside of Novorésumé.

The safety and security of your information also depend on you. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password or access through a unique link on your email address for access to certain parts of Novorésumé, you are responsible for keeping the password and the content in your email inbox confidential. We ask you not to share your password, the unique information that you will receive in your email account or the login link with anyone. We urge you to be careful about giving out information in public areas of Novorésumé like message/comment boards.

The information you choose at your own will to share publicly will be accessible by everyone who has access to that particular software, website/app or service, therefore, we are not able to protect it. By default, all your data is private. However, if you share your application documents on social media through or without our web application, or share your application online on a unique URL, or by email, or in public places of Novorésumé, or by third-party software, websites/apps or services, we cannot guarantee the privacy of the data you have used in those documents and Novorésumé cannot be held liable for what happens to it after you have shared it. Therefore, we would suggest being careful where and with whom you are sharing your documents or other professional information created/shared with Novorésumé.

We have implemented measures designed to secure your private information from accidental loss and unauthorized access, use, alteration, and disclosure. All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers behind firewalls. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not 100% secure. Although we do our best to protect your private information, we cannot guarantee the security of your private information transmitted to Novorésumé. Any transmission of personal information is at your risk. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on Novorésumé. However, our team always strives to keep your information as secure as possible all the time.

## 8\. YOUR RIGHTS AND HOW TO WITHDRAW CONSENTS AND UNSUBSCRIBE

You have certain rights according to the applicable data protection regulation. Some of the rights are rather complex and include exemptions, accordingly you are recommended to read relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights. However, you can find a summary of your rights, if you unfold below sections.

 **8.1 The right to access**

You have a right to obtain the confirmation as to whether or not your personal data are being processed by Novorésumé. In addition, you have a right to obtain more detailed information about the personal data kept and the processing undertaken by us and under certain circumstances the right to receive a copy of this personal data.

 **8.2 The right to rectification**

You have the right to have inaccurate personal data about you rectified, and, taking into account the purpose of the processing, to have incomplete personal data completed.

 **8.3 The right to erasure**

In some cases, you have the right to erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include; i) the personal data is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which it was collected or otherwise processed; ii) you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; iii) the processing is for direct marketing purposes and iv) the personal data has been unlawfully processed. However, there are certain general exclusions of the right to erasure. Those general exclusions include where processing is necessary; i) for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; ii) for compliance with legal obligations; or iii) for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

After some of your personal data was erased based on your request, some copies of it might still be stored in our backups for a maximum of 50 days. The reason why we do not automatically erase the data from our backups is that it might create security risks. If you want more information about this, please contact our Chief Privacy Officer.

 **8.4 The right to restriction of processing**

In some cases, you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Where processing has been restricted, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only otherwise process it i) with your consent; ii) for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; iii) for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or iv) for reasons of important public interest.

 **8.5 The right to data portability**

To the extent the legal basis for the processing is your consent, and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.

 **8.6 The right to object**

You have the right to object to the processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for i) the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in Novorésumé; or ii) the purpose of legitimate interests pursued by us or a third party. In such case we will cease processing the personal data, unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing, which override your interests, rights and freedoms or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

You also have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.

 **8.7 The right to withdraw consent**

To the extent that the legal basis for the processing is your consent, you have the right to withdraw from that consent at any time.

In case you withdraw from a consent given, then we will cease to process your personal data, unless and to the extent the continued processing is permitted or required according to the applicable personal data regulation or other applicable laws and regulations. The withdrawal from your consent will in no event affect the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal.

If you refrain from providing required consents, or later on withdraw from the consents, it might have as a consequence that you may not be able to benefit from some of the service offerings provided by us.

 **8.8 The right to complaint to data protection supervisory authority**

You may always lodge a complaint with your local data protection supervisory authority. The data protection supervisory authority in Denmark, you can find their contact information here.

We do our best to ensure that we protect your personal data, keep you informed about how we process your personal data and comply with the applicable data protection regulation. In case you are not satisfied with the processing and protection of your personal data or the information you have received from us, then we urge you to inform us in order for us to improve. Please also do not hesitate to contact us, if you want to make use of your rights.

Please contact us through the points of contact listed in Our Contact Details. Please also provide us with relevant information to take care of your request, including your full name and email address so that we can identify you. We will respond to your request without undue delay.

You can always withdraw from a consent to receive newsletters etc. and unsubscribe from an e-mail list by following the instructions in any e-mail or other communication you receive from us.

If you have created an account with us, then you can also manage and delete your account by logging into the account and administer your account.

## 9\. Changes to This Privacy Policy

Occasionally Novorésumé might make changes to the Privacy Policy. When such changes are made, Novorésumé will make sure to provide you with prominent notice as appropriate under the circumstances, e.g., by displaying a prominent notice within Novorésumé or by sending you an email. In some cases, we will notify you in advance. Please, therefore, make sure you read any such notice carefully.
